# **ERIK WAIBEL**

#### SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

As a passionate and self-motivated lead JavaScript engineer, I have 5+ years experience in creating production-ready web applications, with a focus on the latest frontend technologies. I increased EBIT by 30% while leading a team of 15+ software developers to a successful global production release for General Motors European brand sites. I helped reduce our team's development time by 20% with implementation of Git flow methodology and best practices. I have strong communication skills and can thrive under any high pressure environment.

**■** ejwaibel+resume@gmail.com

**J** +1 480-331-1899

• https://www.github.com/ejwaibel in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejwaibel

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Lead Frontend Engineer | Vue Developer

iRELO

04/2018 - Present

Principal frontend engineer/architect responsible for building and maintaining 10 single page web applications utilizing latest frontend technology stacks. Design & develop Vue.js components to integrate with new and existing applications across the organization.

- Tune and maximize performance of web applications in order to reduce page load time by 30%, while continuing to learn new patterns and best practices
- Utilized Webpack build integration to perform JavaScript compilation and minification for all frontend development, which reduced final asset sizes by 80%
- Interface with design team and ensure provided assets and layout will conform with best practices for responsive & mobile first
- Coordinate with PM in Asana utilizing an agile process to ensure all bugs & features are completed on time
- Developed custom eslint and stylelint configurations for inclusion with all company projects
- Organized Git standardization and process through Gitlab, while training and supporting developers
- Produced Git CLI script to generate automatic changelog and Gitlab release
- Integrated latest JavaScript standards and ES2017 features

### **Adjunct Faculty**

Chandler Gilbert Community College

01/2018 - Present

Develop and teach 3 courses as an adjunct faculty in the Computer Information Systems department with a focus on web development integrating HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

#### **SKILLS**

Expert				
HTML5	CSS3	JavaScript		
jQuery	SCSS/LESS/PostCSS Git			
NodeJS	REST	ES6/ES2017		
Grunt	Gulp	Perl SDLC		
Agile Method		SCM	L	inux
Intermediate				





#### Lead JavaScript Engineer | Senior Web Developer

General Motors IT - Global Brands

07/2014 - 04/2018

Started as an individual contributor migrating 3rd party web applications into GM ecosystem. Promoted to Principal UI Engineer responsible for end to end feature enablement across the UI layer, and the integration of UI into the broader ecosystem of General Motors brand websites. Increased EBIT by 30% while leading a team of 15+ software developers to a successful global production release for General Motors European brand sites.

- Arhitected JavaScript web components solution with jQuery & TerrificJS called "AtomicJS"
- Lead team of 15+ developers to deliver 65 custom AEM components for the European brands release, which reached 20 different countries
- Implemented solution for functional website integration of social media, Google analytics, and SEO within AEM infrastructure
- Analyzed performance of brand sites and executed plan to increase initial page load time by 30% and decrease asset sizes by 25%
- Applied CSS3 styles to modular components based on PSD styleguides
- Produced multiple angular applications for inclusion into a Bootstrap/Foundation framework
- Designed solution for custom SCSS inheritance to accomodate multiple shared projects
- Designed solution for internal Gulp build process and provided enhancements based on project challenges, which helped decrease build time by 2 hours
- Triaged bugs on a daily basis to ensure issues are resolved in time for production release
- Coordinated with business and design teams to ensure proper requirements for new features
- Researched advanced CSS & JavaScript techniques to implement latest browser features and enhance the customer's experience
- Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment

### Software Engineer II

iTRACS / Commscope

09/2012 - 07/2014

Individual contributor responsible for the construction and implementation of an enterprise class web application providing business critical datacenter management solution. Lead developer for design and implementation of customer portal with multiple WordPress instances. Worked closely with team members in an agile environment to ensure implementation of features/functionality conform to release/business objectives.

- Created and deployed 10+ advanced RESTful API interfaces with PHP and SOAP Web Services, which had to support internal and external API requests
- Developed and maintained a large responsive single-page application supported on all major browsers and mobile devices
- Extended existing jQuery UI widgets with custom component widgets
- Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment
- · Assisted in managing Git merge requests with multiple developers and branches through Gitlab
- Managed product enhancements and defects in a time-senstitive and high pressure agile development process with monthly production releases
- Coordinated with QA to release the initial version of customer-facing single-page web application on time with a team of 3 web developers and 2 web designers.

### **Adjunct Faculty**

Art Institute of Phoenix

09/2010 - 12/2014

Developed and taught 8 courses as an adjunct faculty in the Graphic & Web Design department, with average class size of 12 students.

#### Owner | IT Engineer | Software Developer

Everything Just Works, LLC

05/2010 - 10/2013

Everything Just Works, LLC focused on giving computer users a one-on-one interaction with computer repair gurus. I wanted to empower individuals to use the computer to its full potential and be aware of the problems that can arise so that they aren't stuck paying someone to recover their data. Worked as a software consultant developing custom WordPress integrations for 5 clients.

- Built custom website for Realty Company that would allow users to search for houses based on a given MLS listing.
  - PHP application with IIS 7.5 and Microsoft SQL 2008 database
  - Object Oriented PHP5 from scratch with IIS 7.5 and MSSQL 2008 integration.
  - Developed custom JavaScript algorithm with Google Maps API to calculate distances between multiple addresses
  - Built custom jQuery plugin to generate tabular data records
- Diagnosed and repaired local and small business websites that use WordPress.
- Improved and resolved problems for WordPress websites with custom PHP, jQuery, CSS, and HTML due to incompatible WordPress theme(s) and/or client requests.
- Eradicated viruses and malware from infected computers after performing necessary troubleshooting techniques.

### Software Developer

Insight Global, Contract w/Level 3 Communications

07/2012 - 10/2012

- Developed the internal website on Apache server for network planners using Perl Mason, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS3.
- Configured and administered Bugzilla installation on Linux CentOS server for customer required bug tracking system.
- Provided multiple Perl script reports that would run on a daily/weekly cron job and generate custom Excel spreadsheets for client.
- Created custom internal Perl modules to help with database connections, common utility functions, and Excel spreadsheet customization.

### Systems Engineer

APEX Systems, Contract w/Wells Fargo

10/2011 - 06/2012

- Developed Perl script that would run as a daemon to search specific directories for files.
- Customized in-house Perl modules for better functionality and maintainability.
- Extended Perl scripts to help automate tasks across 15 UNIX Solaris and Linux servers, including threads that would run commands on specified servers in parallel.
- Enhanced current scripts to include the use of Log::Log4Perl in order to generate log files for all output in order to verify steps were completed successfully.
- Provided multi-level support to the Customer Care team and employees that worked directly with Wells Fargo Wholesale customers.

### Software Developer | SCM Consultant

A Better Solution, Inc.

04/2007 - 06/2011

- Implemented Perl scripts to help developers integrate with ClearCase more seamlessly.
- Developed Perl modules for custom ClearCase functionality within our scripts. This allowed to easily and quickly building Perl scripts for custom ClearCase interaction.
- Ensured project builds and releases performed efficiently and correctly through the use of IBM Rational BuildForge.
- Produced automated build scripts using Perl and shell programming.
- Administered UNIX & Windows machines for the IT group whenever necessary.
- Provided first level technical assistance to end users including, but not limited to: replicating errors, resolving application issues, and investigating errors.

#### Jr. PHP Developer

BlueHornet.com

09/2006 - 04/2007

Junior PHP developer helping to enhance the existing web application with custom Object Oriented code for quicker development and easier maintainability. Coordinated with the graphic design team and integrated Photoshop layouts using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Documented new features thoroughly for use with customer support documentation.

#### **EDUCATION**

### B.S., Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University

09/2001 - 08/2006

Erik Waibel — 480-331-1899 — ejwaibel+resume@gmail.com

\*Generated from Markdown with: https://github.com/there4/markdown-resume